

Yener Bas
Front End Developer
(information-electron
ics technician)

Yener BasNievenheimerstr. 1 50739 Köln

0049/176 7672 55 63 yener.bas@outlook.de

Portfolio: <u>www.yener-bas.de</u> LinkedIn: <u>My LinkedIn Profil</u>

About Me

I am a German-speaking Front End Web Developer with experience in creating web apps with JavaScript & Angular. You can find my responsive websites and business apps comprehensively in my public portfolio. I started my IT journey with an apprenticeship as an information electronics technician and I discovered my interest in coding at the age of 15 and started building simple websites with HTML & CSS. While working as an IT admin for a large hospital, I decided that I wanted to expand my coding skills and to focus on software development full time. After building a myriad of projects I am looking forward to building on my first experience and starting my career in IT in a junior developer position.

Main Stack:

- JavaScript
- TypeScript, Angular
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Side Stack:

- Git, APIs (REST), Google Firebase

Skills

- Building Applications with JavaScript & Angular: I built landing
 pages and several web apps as well as OOP-based Jump and Run
 Games. In various projects, we were working with Github
 collaboration and also coded live together.
- Deep understanding of IT & Software: Due to my background as an IT and electronics specialist, I do understand computer software and hardware very well.
- **High sense of responsibility:** I am used to taking responsibility and working diligently as I always did in my job as an information-electronics technician.

Professional Experience

Maera GmbH / Webentwickler und IT Support (Minijob)

JUL 2023 - TODAY, COLOGNE

- Responsibility for all electronic devices.
- Detailed processing of Tickets in the home office or throughout the company on site.
- Web development with Wordpress, Docker, Ninox and more

Universitätsklinikum Köln (Robert Half GmbH) / IT-Administrator

MAR 2021 - NOV 2021, COLOGNE

- Responsibility for all printing devices.
- Detailed processing of Tickets remote or throughout the clinic on site
- Internal Customer Service in German, English & Turkish.

Office-/information-electronics technician / Several Employers (Malteser Hilfsdienst e.V., BT-Kopier GmbH, lang informationssysteme GmbH & Co.KG, Printcom GmbH)

MAR 2010 - MAR 2021, COLOGNE, BONN, ESSEN, OBERHAUSEN, DÜSSELDORF

- Service technician throughout Europe with the highest Kyocera certification.
- Contact person for everything in the entire scope, especially for printers, copiers and multifunction devices as well as for most devices in an office and its network.
- I have Europe-wide experience in the areas of an in-house technician, rollout team, and service technician in the field in private and business areas.

Education

Developer Akademie / JavaScript & Angular Web Development Training

APR 2022 - AUG 2022, MUNICH

Project based coding academy. Main Stack: JavaScript, Angular

Portfolio: www.yener-bas.de

Extensive Coding School, Learning Front-End Development, Coding, Agile Project Management and building several projects in teams and alone.

Georg-Simon-Ohm Berufsschule / Fachoberschulreife mit Qualifikation

AUG 2006 - JAN 2010, COLOGNE

Apprenticeship as an office-/information-electronics technician.

Languages

German: native
Türkish: native

English: good